[
  {
    "question": "Q. What is a sacrament?",
    "answer": "A. A sacrament is a holy ordinance instituted by Christ, wherein, by sensible signs, Christ and the benefits of the new covenant are represented, sealed, and applied to believers. (WSC 92) (Gal. 3:27; 1 Cor. 10:16)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. How many sacraments?",
    "answer": "A. Christ instituted two sacraments in His church.<br>Two: Baptism and the Lord’s Supper. Matt. 28:18-20 indicates the commandment to baptize believers (note – there is no commandment to continue circumcision). In Matt. 26:26-29, Mark 14:22-25, Luke 22:14-19, and 1 Cor. 11:23-30, Jesus (and Paul) commands His followers to participate in the Lord’s Supper or Communion.<br>Baptism replaced the Old Testament covenantal sign of circumcision, and the Lord’s Supper took the place of the Old Testament Passover meal."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. How are sacraments a sign?",
    "answer": "A. A sign is the physical element (water, bread, wine) that points to the spiritual reality (union with Christ, forgiveness of sins)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. How are sacraments a seal?",
    "answer": "A. A seal is a confirmation or guarantee that the spiritual reality is truly present and being conveyed to the believer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q.What does “sacramental union” mean?",
    "answer": "A. The relationship between the sign and the thing signified — when we call the bread the body of Christ."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who may administer the sacraments?",
    "answer": "A. A lawfully ordained minister. Sacraments are tied to the ministry of the Word (Matt. 28), and ministers are called and ordained to serve as Christ’s representatives (1 Cor. 4; Titus 1)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. How are sacraments related to the written and preached Word?",
    "answer": "A. The Word and the sacraments:<br>- Have the same author (2 Tim. 3:16; 1 Cor. 11:23-25)<br>- Have the same content (1 Cor. 1:23; 11:26)<br>- Require faith as the means to appropriate the content (1 Cor. 1:21; Col. 2:12)<br>But the Word takes priority over the sacraments, because it:<br>- Is essential for salvation, while the sacraments are not (Rom. 10:14-15; 4:11)<br>- Engenders and strengthens faith, while the sacraments only strengthen it (Rom.10:17; Gal. 3:26-27)<br>- Is intended for the whole world, while the sacraments are only intended for the church (Rom.10:12-17; Eph. 2:11-12)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. How are the sacraments effectual?",
    "answer": "A. The sacraments become effectual, not from any virtue in them, or in him that does administer them; but only by the blessing of Christ, and the working of his Spirit in them that by Faith receive them. (WSC 91)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What sacraments of the Old Testament are tied to the sacraments of the New Testament?",
    "answer": "A. Circumcision to Baptism: Circumcision, the sign of the covenant with Abraham (Genesis 17:10-11), marked inclusion in God’s covenant community. In the New Testament, baptism replaces circumcision as the sign of the covenant (Colossians 2:11-12).<br><br>Passover to the Lord’s Supper: The Passover commemorated Israel's deliverance from Egypt through the blood of the lamb (Exodus 12:21-27). The Lord’s Supper, instituted by Christ during Passover (Luke 22:19-20), fulfills this by pointing to Jesus, the Lamb of God (1 Corinthians 5:7), whose sacrifice delivers believers from sin."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What is baptism?",
    "answer": "A. Baptism is a sacrament, wherein the washing with water, in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost (Matt. 28), does signify and seal our ingrafting into Christ (Gal. 3); and partaking of the benefits of the covenant of grace (Acts 2); and our engagement to be the Lord's (Rom. 6)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What is the language of sign and seal in baptism?",
    "answer": "A. Baptism is an outward sign of one’s allegiance to and ownership by Jesus Christ. We are baptized into the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit. Hence, baptism serves as a public sign indicating one’s desire to be identified with God. Baptism is the visible ratification on the part of God that He indeed does forgive the sins of those who believe in the Lord Jesus Christ. (Rom. 4:11; Gen. 9:12-13; 17:11). The term 'seal' means that baptism is a guarantee and confirmation of the grace which it signifies (Rom. 2; 4; Ex. 12). This relates to paedo-baptism because when an infant is baptized, God is marking that child as His, and providing confirmation of His promise to bestow on that child the blessings of the covenant of grace."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What is the reason to baptize infants?",
    "answer": "A. As the covenant sign of the OT was applied to infant males in circumcision, we baptize infants because they are included in the covenantal promise which is \"for you and your children\", and the children of believers are to be received into the covenant community and given the connected sign and seal (Acts 2, 16)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Explain the relationship between baptism and regeneration.",
    "answer": "A. Baptism is an outward sign, a visible setting apart and reminder of God’s promise. Regeneration is the work of the Spirit and is not tied to baptism as a necessary result. Of those being baptized after confessing their faith in and obedience unto Christ, baptism is a 'sign and seal… of regeneration' (WCF 28.1)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who is to be baptized?",
    "answer": "A. Those who profess faith and obedience in Jesus Christ and the infant children of believing parents (one, or both) – WCF 27.4. For profession of faith baptism, see Acts 2 (Peter on Pentecost), Mark 16:15-16 (Jesus and His Great Commission), Acts 8 (Ethiopian Eunuch). For infant baptism see Gen. 17, Acts 2, 1 Cor. 7 (unbelieving spouse and children are sanctified by the believing spouse), Mark 10 and Luke 18 – where Jesus blesses the little children."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What is the Lord's Supper?",
    "answer": "A. The Lord’s Supper is a sacrament wherein, by giving and receiving of bread and wine, according to Christ’s appointment, his death is showed forth; and worthy receives are, not after a corporal and carnal manner, but by faith made partakers of his body and blood, to their spiritual nourishment, and growth in grace."
  },

  {
    "question": "Q. What is communion 'under both kinds'?",
    "answer": "A. Communion 'under both kinds' refers to the practice of administering the Eucharist in both forms—both the consecrated bread (the body of Christ) and the consecrated wine (the blood of Christ) to the laity."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What are the four major view of the Lord's Supper?",
    "answer": "A. Transubstantiation - the bread and wine are miraculously turned into the physical body and blood of Christ.<br><br>Consubstantiation – the physical presence of Christ locally fills the elements (in, on and around the bread and wine).<br><br>Memorialist – holds that the Lord's Supper is strictly a memorial to Christ's death and nothing else. Zwingli was not truly a 'bare memorialist' because he said the church was the body of Christ and the mystical work happened to the people, not the elements.<br><br>Reformed – The elements remain unchanged during the Lord's Supper, yet Christ is present, and believers enjoy a mystical communion with Him, nourishing and strengthening one's soul through the mediating work of the Holy Spirit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Is Christ in any sense present in the Lord's Supper? If so, how?",
    "answer": "A. Through the Holy Spirit believers are lifted up to partake of Christ’s body and blood in a real, though mystical, way, receiving the benefits of His sacrifice by faith. Christ is not present physically or locally in the elements."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who should take part in the Lord's Supper?",
    "answer": "A. Those who are of years and ability to examine themselves—generally those who have made professions of faith. Paedocommunion is denied in WLC 177 and 1 Cor. 11."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. How is 'fencing the table' practiced during communion?",
    "answer": "A. By reading the words of institution from either a gospel account or 1 Cor. 11, all are made aware this is an ordinance instituted by Christ. It is observed in remembrance of Christ and his death is showed forth until he comes again, and God works through this meal as a means of grace. Those who are communicants in good standing in any evangelical church or been approved by the session are invited to participate while others are invited to remain and observe."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who may be kept from the Lord's table?",
    "answer": "A. Such as are found to be <u>ignorant or scandalous</u>, notwithstanding their profession of the faith, and desire to come to the Lord's Supper, may and ought to be kept from that sacrament, by the power which Christ has left in his church, until they receive instruction, and manifest their reformation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. How do we handle 1 Corinthians 11 and padeo-communion?",
    "answer": "A. The PCA has rejected padeo-communion as an error in its position paper and argues that Paul in 1 Corinthians 11 sets forth the requirement of being able to 'examine themselves so that they may distinguish the body of the Lord and not eat and drink unworthily.'"
  }
]
